# Jagadeeswar Venkatasubbu

Tech Lead/Full Stack Engineer

jagadeeswarvenkatasubbu@gmail.com (+61) 0469 754 506 <u>Github</u> <u>GitHub Woolworths</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> Permanent Residence Bridging Visa (NSW Sponsored)

# Summary

8+ years of Software Industry experience across a range of technologies. Strong track record of agile delivery, utilising latest technologies. Expert in hands on software architecture (including microservice architectures), agile practices, cloud adoption, DevOps, continuous delivery and cloud native technologies. Incrementally built and replaced legacy systems with modern solutions.

### Skills

- Java
- Kotlin
- Typescript
- Scala
- Kafka
- WebFlux

- React JS
- Spring Boot
- Terraform
- Kubernetes
- SAP Commerce

# Specializations

- Micro Services
- DevOps
- Continuous Delivery
- GitOps

## Cloud Experience

- Azure
- AWS

# Development Practices

- Agile
- Test DrivenDevelopment
- Pair Programming

### Data Stores

- MySql
- SQL Server
- DynamoDB
- Redis
- KSqlDB

# Education and Certification

- Graduated in B-Tech Information Technology, Anna University, Chennai
- SAP Commerce Certified

# Other Interests

- Fitness Enthusiast
- Fitness Blogging
- Badminton
- Hiking

Beaches

# Experience

### Tata Consultancy Services

#### 2012 - Present

#### BigW X

Tech Lead/Full Stack Engineer

April 2019 - Present

- Played a pivotal role in transforming a large monolith application into modern event-driven microservices based application.
- Practised DevOps, Continuous Delivery and Test Driven Development.
- Gained huge expertise in using kafka for event driven applications. Have used Kafka Streams DSL and Processor API to build and transform topics. Have also introduced KSQLDB in the ecosystem to improve the ease of creating Kafka streams and tables for applications.
- Have always been strategical and pragmatic at the same time to ensure we add more value while we transform a large monolith with the stranglers pattern.
- Delivered multiple initiatives by figuring out the right MVP for the initiative and iteratively delivered more value for the initiative.
- As a team player have been highly interested in delivering and measuring value. Have been a big believer on measuring the value delivered for each initiative.
- Actively involved in keeping a large distributed team on-board with the strategical direction on the technology transformation and initiative delivery.
- Created and managed infrastructure resource, Kafka, Kubernetes, supporting applications(like monitoring, observability, traceability, etc) and application deployments.
- Delivered multiple initiates, which includes adding multiple delivery service, enabling multi carrier solutions, improving the store process with the backoffice applications by creating an all new availability, sourcing, delivery, carrier and fulfilment services.
- Implemented a wait-room solution for keeping the high traffic of customers on a separate wait lounge website, where the customers will be put on a queue and be redirected to the main website when the traffic in the main website completes their purchase.
- Contributed highly in improving the performance of the website.

#### Woolworths Shout

### Tech Lead/Full Stack Engineer

January 2019 - March 2019

- Practised DevOps and Infrastructure as Code with Google
- Built a backoffice application with ReactJS as frontend and with Python for the backend service.
- Implemented enterprise google auth for the application.
- Implemented multiple views of predictions from machine learning for the store team to identify
  and fill the stocks that were sold out on the shelves.
- Created an interactive push notification for the backoffice application to notify store team upon every predictions.

#### Woolworths Wholesale Portal

#### Solution Architect

September 2017 - December 2018

- Played the role of solution architect for Woolworths wholesale e-commerce solution starting from the discovery to implementation.
- Involved in various workshops to understand the broader wholesale requirements and designed the application based on the needs of the business.
- Provided in depth consultation and solution for the wholesale e-commerce application.
- Led the team to create the infrastructure required for the applications with Terraform in Microsoft Azure.
- Practised Continuous Delivery and DevOps to deliver multiple microservices to support the ecommerce application.
- Designed a very highly available active-active DR strategy.
- Provided solution and design for the master & transactional data integration with different systems like SAP ERP, SAP PMR, Woolworths in-house Article Enrichment System, Sail Point, etc.
- Designed and implemented article ranging and customer specific pricing on the application along with personalised search capabilities for the same.
- Built the CI/CD pipeline in Azure DevOps.
- Implemented zero downtime deployment for the e-commerce solution.
- Implemented performance test for the entire solution with Gatling.

#### EIS

#### Tech Lead

#### July 2016 - August 2017

- Led the team technically in the design and delivery of a complex B2B e-commerce solution.
- Designed and integrated payment gateway solution in the website.
- Efficiently implemented a complex pricing service to fulfil the complex requirement of customer specific pricing for the B2B needs.
- Customized and orchestrated the cart and checkout flow for e-commerce website.
- Integrated with TIBCO for customer, contact person, sold to and ship to addresses, product, prices, inventory, customer part number, tax calculations and sales order.
- Pivotal in productionisation of the applications.

### Apple Inc.

#### Tech Lead

April 2016 - June 2016

- Led the solution to integrate SAP commerce for Apple Inc.'s B2B commerce application with SAP ERP and SAP CRM through Data-hub as the integration platform.
- Designed and developed a scalable and efficient solution for selling configurable products

#### Mitre10 NZ

### Senior Developer

February 2016 - March 2016

- Customized checkout flow for home delivery and pick up in store options for Mitre 10.
- Integrated with Google APIs to identify the nearest store to reserve stock and fulfil the order for home delivery option.
- Designed and created page for recalled products and provided a backoffice dashboard to manage the recalled products for the business users.
- Designed and implemented an automated content migrations process for complex pages like "Do it yourself" and "Guides and Advices" from the legacy system to a modern content management system for the website.
- Efficiently separated mitre10 retail and trade codebase with two separate storefronts and services layers, which before had same storefront and services, which was very cumbersome and complex to manage for the developers.

### Tata Cliq

### Senior Developer

July 2015 - January 2016

- Pivotal in improving the performance of the website.
- Designed and customized checkout flow in the website and customer support backoffice application.
- Designed and integrated order fulfillment flow with order management system.
- Designed and delivered a dashboard application with D3.js and Angular, which shows metrics and data on the sellers workflow status, article enrichment status, etc.

#### Big W

#### Developer

August 2014 - June 2015

- Designed and integrated with Mirakl, a SaaS seller portal solution for marketplace e-commerce systems.
- Integrated with SAP ERP system for in-store price and stock visibility on the website.
- Integrated with parcel point, which provides parcel lockers and pick-up location to enable click and collect as a fulfilment method in the website.
- Integrated payment gateway and gift card payments in the e-commerce website.
- Efficiently altered the cart behaviour of SAP Commerce to enable marketplace ability where a product can be sold by multiple vendors,
- Orchestrated order sourcing for the marketplace solution based on different vendors on the same order.
- Designed and integrated with Google and facebook marketing.

#### Retail Multichannel CoE

### Developer

September 2012 - July 2014

- Gained extensive knowledge and experience in Retail and e-commerce by assisting in wide range of consultations.
- Created multiple assets for SAP Commerce which includes enabling of social sign-on with Gigya, enabling wishlist, data processing utilities and operational utilities like clearing a particular cache across cluster, changing configurations across cluster, monitoring dashboard for cronjobs.
- Proactive and organised in demonstrating the capabilities of the assets and showcasing the multichannel experience in pre-sales and sales for multiple clients.
- Contributed in consultation and proposals for multiple clients.